JORDAN WALKER

E-Mail: Jordanswalker28@gmail.com Tel: 07727 899910 Address: Flat D, 14 Denbigh Road, London, W13 8PX, United Kingdom GitHub: https://github.com/JordanWalker28

PERSONAL PROFILE

Hands-on, experienced Software Developer with a First-Class Honours Degree in Computer Science with specialisation in Artificial Intelligence who has a keen interest in evolving technologies and ambition to continuously develop. In the process of developing in Cloud Computing by completing online modules for the AWS Certified Developer Associate exam.

KEY TECHNICAL SKILLS

Agile and Kanban Software Development Methodologies, Bootstrap, CSS, Docker, Full-Stack, Git Version Control, HTML, Java, JavaScript, Jenkins, JSPs, MySQL, NoSQL, C# and .Net development, Node.js, PostgreSQL, PHP, Python, SQL Server

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Developer - February 2021 - Present TradingHub, London, United Kingdom https://tradinghub.com/team/

In my role of Full Stack Developer, a large focus has been on autonomously developing the front-end UI/UX whilst also identifying and solving problems in the back-end for the analysis tool that is provided to a wide range of clients for evaluating their brokers' trading execution.

Key Achievements:

- Key-contributor in implementing interactions to visual items of the product platform which has had a positive impact on customer experience for controlling their data visualisations
- Improved and increased accuracy of a shared code area, used by all TradingHub products, to effectively capture user graphs with greater performance and create relevant customer alerts
- Increased maintainability and performance of the UI codebase through extensive refactoring which has led to shorter turnaround times when introducing features and proof of concepts
- Established the interface within the "TEAM" product that allows users to view arising issues with their uploaded trades

Responsibilities:

- Continuously developing and maintaining the visual representations of customers' data by introducing new code, maintaining existing code and reviewing customer feedback
- Effective prioritising within a Kanban environment whilst taking ownership of resolving GitLab features and arising issues
- Maintaining best code practices by reviewing and offering feedback on merge requests
- Actively supporting on projects planning by contributing to product performance reviews and development meetings
- Investigating for issue causes and suggesting robust solutions that support the implementation of new features

Software Developer - September 2019 - February 2021 Insightsoftware, London, United Kingdom https://insightsoftware.com/hubble/

As a Back-End Developer within Insightsoftware, I was working on improving and developing features for the company's custom integration ERP software "Hubble" within C#'s .Net-framework.

Key Achievements:

- Customised the company's own end-user licence agreement by developing an application that could also be adopted for other products within the company
- Commended by a client and wider team for efficiently solving a number of tickets related to their usability of the product
- Exposed to front-end development by updating the branding to new guidelines set by the wider business
- Increased the performance of the product's web application by removing dependencies
- Ensured that the code of both greenfield and brownfield development features had robust, clean, bug-free and reliable before being released to clients
- As part of my personal goals, I integrated various technologies and frameworks used in

Hubble into a tech radar which gave the team easy access to review technological dependencies and was further on presented to the wider engineering team due to positive recognition

Responsibilities:

- Created unit tests as well as running self-developed and automated integration tests through "Hubble's" Jenkins pipeline
- Resolved tickets raised by clients and the customer service team
- Active Involvement in sprint planning and setting goals (Scrum environment) whilst also regularly led daily stand-up sessions through which the team communicated sprint objectives and potential progress issues
- Thoroughly assessed the pre-released product by testing manually and running automated regression tests
- Continuously developed and maintained the code pipeline through Jenkins
- Active involvement in developing features that allowed the software to utilise clients' cloud-based databases
- Investigated technologies, frameworks and procedures to aid in making design decisions and captured the information into the company's documentation store so that it could be easily accessed

Lab Assistant – September 2018 – April 2019, Heriot-Watt University, Edinburgh

Assisted the first, and second-year students with questions about assignments and practical
labs in the subjects of Software Development, Web Design & Databases and Web
Programming by supporting their problem-solving processes and providing them with an
understanding to the cause of certain errors and issues

Previous positions between and during University programmes:

Various positions in Tourism and Retail – June 2012 – June 2019

- Quick-learning abilities led to being promoted into a supervisor position where supportive leadership skills were required when training new employees on how to deal with customer queries, cashiering and day-to-day business responsibilities
- Demonstrated sound interpersonal skills when communicating with customers while upholding a professional company image when dealing with their queries or grievances

EDUCATION

BA (Hons), Computer Science (with specialisation in Artificial Intelligence) Graduated with Honours of the First Class - September 2015 - June 2019, Heriot-Watt University, Edinburgh

- Through outstanding research, the dissertation upon completion was awarded the "Cooper-Walker Engineering prize" for best project of the school and was nominated by the University for Scotland's "Young Software Engineer of the Year Award"
- Gained sound strategic abilities through a group project that included working with students of little to no prior communication to build a fully functioning web application
- Utilised knowledge in machine learning to develop a project with cohorts which included developing the group's own conversational agent using a wide variety of programming languages
- Demonstrated ambition and motivation which led to receiving multiple scholarships from the university for merit of grades

BTEC Level 3 National Extended Diploma with a Triple Grade Distinction* in Information Technology - September 2013 – June 2015, Carlisle College, Carlisle

VOLUNTARY EXPERIENCE

- Vice President of the Graphic Design Society at Heriot-Watt University
- Elected Programme Representative at Heriot-Watt University
- Acting as a tutor to secondary school pupils for the 'Hour of Code' at Carlisle College